Nguyen Hai Dang

Go Vap District, Ho Chi Minh City



BIOGRAPHY

until destiny knocked in the form of our family's first computer when I was twelve-year-old. It was "love at first sight" – yeah, I was that kid who fell head over heels for a PC. I asked my parents to buy a monthly subscription of Echip - the only "computer" magazine in Vietnam and my only source of knowledge at the time (around 2005). And then 2008, The Internet has finally reached our house. I got drawn right into Yahoo! Chat, Google, hacking... and Pascal. That is how it all started.

- 2005: Broke first hard drive, 1 motherboard, 1 DVD disc drive... and got a beating more times than I'd like to admit.
- 2007: Masterminded a piggy bank heist to buy my first Flash USB flash drive (an USB completed with a dazzling flash light). Spoiler alert: got caught, of course a good ol' fashioned beating.
- 2010: Ascended to the majestic titles of Moderator of Joomla! on the ITVNN forum (big deal back then) and Local Attack box Moderator of VHC - Vietnamese Hacking Community. Started earning money by creating websites with Joomla! (and miraculously avoided any more beatings). At 17.

And I started to love the PHP language. Stuck with it since then. (To be honest, I started a love affair with Python and Data Science) I forsaken Pascal:

Also, I've completed my Master Degree in Software Engineering at FPT University right on my 30th birthday.

EDUCATION

♦ FPT University	Jun 2019 - Dec 2023
Master in Software Engineering	
Ranking: 8.3	
♦ FPT University	Sep 2011 - Dec 2015

Bachelor in Software Engineering

Ranking: 7.16

SKILLS

SKILLS	
Micro-services Architecture	 Communication channels: RabbitMQ, Kafka, Elastic Search Database-per-service or using Schemas Experienced in breaking legacy Monolith to Micro-services, improved a critical Lab Result module TAT time from 3 months to under 3 minutes Experienced in Ecommerce crawler system
PHP	 Over 9 years of experiences Worked with: Laravel (>8 years) CakePHP Yii 2 Symphony
Python	- Django: 2 year of experience - For data, ML, AI
DevOps	 - Kubernetes setup - Terraform - Jenkins - HelmCharts - AWS Cloud
Design pattern and practices	 MVC SOLID, DRY, KISS, YAGNI Clean Code & The Clean Coder by RR. Martin are some of my favorite books in SE. Ask me a chapter :D jk Dependency Injection Repository Micro-services TDD & BDD
Artificial Inteligence	Studied Computer VisionCan design CNN models for handling pattern matching or detections

	- My thesis about making of a light-weight CNN model to detect a wide range of emotion in realtime. Since its light weight, it can be embedded easily. You can find more information in the PDF here https://github.com/socrec/restauai-thesis-paper/
Others	 - FE skills: ReactJS, VueJS, NobleUI (Laravel Blade), Filament, Livewire. - Experienced in Agile, Scrum (Nexus Scrum,) Studied in-depth about Agile as part of MSE degree. - Experienced in managing teams of 5-10
	- Well-versed in best-practices for SQL database
	- Throughout knowledge in GIT (Branching, Work Flow, best practices)
	- Knowledgable in DevOps task: Can setup and training staffs to use CI/CD.
	- Have FE knowledge. Can work with other languages or manage FE devs
	- Welcoming attitude when it comes to learning something new
	- Wordpress (a little)
	- Photoshop (>7 years, I am an amateur photographer)
	- Good English
	- 我可以一点点中文。
	- 私は少し日本語を知っています。

CERTIFICATIONS AND AWARDS

Master Degree in Software Engineering	
Coursera Deep Learning Specialization Certificate ID: EPPRX6ZM6ADX	2020
Coursera Python for Everybody Specialization Certificate ID: ZMMKW49FUVA5	2020
30% Scholarship for Master in Software Engineering course at FPT University	2019
Excellent Staff of the 2016 Fourth Quarter by 3Si JSC	2017
Information Technology Passport Certificate by VITEC - 675/800 points	2016
Highest Score in Annual English Exam by 3Si JSC	2016
Excellence diploma of Internship – by DOS Company and FPT University	2014
Capstone Project got Highest Grade in the Board of Capstone Projects	2015
Level 6 Academic preparatory English Course Completion Certificate, FPT University (Equal TOEIC 800++, IELTS 6.0)	2015
Certificate of Merit of Fall and Summer Semester	2014

RECENT PROJECTS

Diag Laboratories System - https://diag.vn/

(Dec 2020 - Now)

Customer	Diag Laboratories
Description	Work as Lead Backend Developer. Develop a robust Backend and APIs for mobile and web clients to use. Peak day through-put around 16,000 orders.
Team size	15
My position	Lead Backend Developer
My responsibilities	- Code the backend from scratch Migrate the huge monolith application into services while maintaining 99% uptime - Improved performance of important modules (Lab test results, notification pipelines,). Especially the Lab test result pdf, it had many problems, I removed the bottle-neck and improve the design. Result is 100% no missing pdf AND result time decreased from 3 hours to 3 minutes - Define Coding standard, Conventions document and make sure everyone adhere
Technologies used	Micro-services, data warehouse, Kafka, Lazy migration, Laravel 10

Powersell - https://powersell.com/

(Jan 2020 - Nov 2020)

Customer	Datamart

Description	Worked as Project manager and Senior coder for 2 projects - PowerPaint: A tool to mass decorate seller's products on multiple ecom platforms at once - Social Commerce: Manager your Instagram, Facebook, Zalo AIO - The company was acquired by a big player in Ecom
Team size	10
My position	Lead developer, Project Manager
My responsibilities	- Lead & manage the team - Hands-on coding and SA designing from scratch
Technologies used	Micro-services, data warehouse, ecom platforms API, Crawler system, Realtime messaging

Freedom Invest - https://www.freedominvest.com/

(Mar 2019 - Jan 2020)

Customer	Freedom Invest
Description	I worked as the lead developer for this project. The biggest challenge was the 3rd party API and all the Finance knowledge that I was lack of. This requires intensive self-learning ability
Team size	5
My position	Lead Developer
My responsibilities	- Lead & manage the developers - Code the Backend from scratch
Technologies used	Python, Django, AWS EC2, RDS

EXPERIENCE

♦ Diag Laboratories Dec 2020 - Now

Senior Software Engineer

Programming in Python/PHP.Building a Micro-services system for taking examination results from various machines and systems to orchestrate and serve it to Doctors and Patients via multiple platforms like mobile app and website. My job now focus only on technical aspect.

- Tech stack: Laravel, Kafka, Micro-services, PostgreSql, GCP.
- Team management: Agile Scrum & Jira.
- Team size: 20

♦ Datamart Solutions Pte Ltd

Jan 2020 - Dec 2020

Senior Principal Engineer

- In charge of Social Commerce & PowerPaint module for PowerSell.From building features requirement with PO team, to coding base, managing teams from the ground up.
- Working with oversea teams on a BI project, fron A-Z.
- Tech stack: Laravel, Social platforms, MongoDB, MySQL, RabbitMQ, E-commerce crawler, big data.
- Team management: Agile Scrum & Jira.
- Team size: 5 10

♦ Launch Deck, LLC

Aug 2018 - Jan 2020

Senior Developer/Projects Leader

- Daily communication and get requirements directly with the clients from US
- The company software division is still young, so I helped to stabilize stuffs, and helped to define a development process
- Manage Jira and Confluence
- Develop projects in Python, NodeJS and PHP

♦ Infinity Core (Singapore based)

Mar 2017 - Jul 2018

Project Manager - PHP Tech lead

- Create SRS, documents
- Track project's progress
- Manage team members
- Responsible for training and technical sharing between members
- Responsible for improving development processes
- Apply Agile (Scrum) with tools like Redmine, Team City (include setting up all tools)

♦ 3S Intersoft jsc Nov 2016 - Feb 2017

Product Manager of several projects

- Develop Web service, Android applications, iOS applications
- Sale & Marketing & Customer Support for ShopApp.vn

- Work as Project Leader of a development team of 8 people
- Manage and develop the whole product, from both business and development perspective
- Develop core component for http://shopapp.vn/- Training new PHP developers

♦ 3S Intersoft jsc Apr 2016 - Oct 2016

PHP developer

- Develop Web services, platforms, applications match customer's need
- Develop core components for http://crisis.vn/

♦ FSoft - FPT Software Dec 2015 - Feb 2016

PHP, Angular2 developer

- Learn and develop a frontend framework for the customer's developers in AngularJS 2 Beta (very in-depth)
- Write a tool for Temando Testing team in PHP
- * Reason of resignation: Work environment does not match intention to be a Bridge SE

♦ DOS - Digital Optimization Solution Joint Stock Company

Jan 2014 - Sep 2014

PHP developer

- Develop company's main product: 10ffice
- Customize 10ffice to match customer's needs
- * Reason of resignation: continue studying at FPT University.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

For more information about me and my career, please visit

My Blog: http://dangnh.cf

My Quora: https://www.quora.com/profile/Mark-Nguyen-96

My Linkedin:

My Coursera Profile: https://www.coursera.org/learner/dang-nguyen-h-8507